Hello and welcome back. In this video we're going to learn about
【未完成版本】欢迎回来 在这个视频里 我们将学习Roto Brush
Roto Brush. Roto Brush is the video segmentation
Roto Brush是After Effects (以下简称AE) 内置的视频分割算法
algorithm inside After Effects. After Effects is the video processing
AE 是Adobe公司开发的视频处理软件
product from Adobe. And Roto Brush was released around April
产品 Roto Brush 随着当时新版本的AE
2010 with a new version of After Effects that was released at that time.
在2010年4月发布
And it was considered one of the highlights of that new release.
是那一版AE的亮点之一
So I think it's very cool to learn about the basic concepts behind Roto Brush.
所以我觉得学习Roto Brush背后的基本概念挺酷的
So let's dive right in. When we are doing video segmentation, and
那让我们直奔主题吧 当我们进行视频分割时
in particular, if we're doing video segmentation for products that are going
如果被分割的对象是将要面世的产品素材
to be used, for example in advertising or the movie industry, we need some very
如广告业或电影行业中的素材 我们的分割需要具备
basic characteristics that need to hold. We need very high accuracy.
一些基本特征 比如 非常高的像素精度
We need to be able to segmentation at the pixel, or even sub pixel level.
我们需要在像素甚至次像素级别上对素材进行分割
As we saw, these are very challenging problems, so the user is going to have to
可想见 高精度分割这一难题所面临的挑战 所以用户必须参与到处理过程中来
be in the loop. And we want to make sure, that the way
而且我们要确保 用户是以非常舒适的方式
the user is involved in the process, is a very comfortable way for the user.
参与到整个过程中的
And, if the user is involved, this has to be done basically in real time.
另外 用户与计算机的交互必须实时完成
You cannot request from the user to do something, then go home, come a few hours
你不能要求用户操作完后回家 几小时之后再回来看结果
later, and see what are the results. You need the user to interact.
你需要让用户与计算机实时交互
In real time with a computer and those are basic characteristics that any one of
这些就是这类算法所需要具备的基本特征
these type of systems needs to have, and certainly Roto Brush has.
当然 Roto Brush具备这些特征
Now we need high quality. So we will need to be able to segment the
我们需要高质量的分割
videos with very, very high quality to get to the sub-pixel levels to be able to
并且让分割出来的视频精度能达到次像素级
do that and this is a video that we have seen before.
然后 这是我们之前看过的一个视频例子 （我们想把其中的两个运动员分割出来）
Now why is this so challenging? For a number of reasons.
为什么分割视频如此具有挑战性？ 有许多原因
Some of them we have seen, and some of them I want to go back to them.
其中一些我们已经了解了 其中的一些我们稍后再提及
So these are some of the challenges that we encounter.
这就是我们面临的一些挑战
And we encounter them in the video, we also encountered them also in the images.
先前我们在处理图像时遇到过它们 现在处理视频也一样
And that's why I basically using stills here as well to you to describe.
这也是这儿我仍然使用照片来描述的原因
What is overlapping color distribution? What do I mean by that?
什么是叠加着色分布？这是什么意思？
We saw in the previous. Slide that I want to segment out these
在上一张幻灯片中提到了我想把这两位运动员分割出来
two players. But look.
但注意看
This player has a white shirt and also people in the audience have white shirts.
这位运动员穿的是白色上衣 观众中也有人穿的是白色上衣
This player has a blue shirt, there's also blue here, there's blue here,
另一位选手穿的是蓝色上衣 这也有蓝色 那也有
there's blue here. So basically there is a lot of
这有蓝色 总之图里有很多重复的颜色
overlapping colors. We discussed that early on, it looks like
我们之前讨论过 颜色相近的前景和背景将导致
color enough and therefore edges are not going to be sufficient to do an accurate
不再有足够的的边缘信息帮助我们准确地分割
segmentation. Here is another examples where edges are
这是另外一个边缘信息不足够导致无法准确分割的例子
not going to be sufficient. There is basically no boundaries here.
在这里 几乎没有边界
So how do we know to segment out the car if I don't really see where the car ends?
当我们根本看不到车的轮廓的时 将车分割出来便无从谈起
Additional challenges that appear, in particular in video is that they are
同时也出现了新的挑战 特别是在视频领域
what's called topological changes. So look how they are and here separated
存在所谓的拓扑变化 我们来看看是怎样变化的
from the body. In one of the next frames it's actually
这的手臂是不触碰身体的 而在之后的几帧中 手臂触碰到了身体
touching the body and this hole has been created.
同时生成了这个洞
So the actual shape, the global shape of the object of interest, is changing.
所以 我们所关注物体的实际形状 或者说总体形状是在变化着的
And once again, it's changing here. There is a new host.
在这 又改变了一次 换了一个新宿主
So there's a lot of variability because of the articulation.
因而视频的动态衔接带来了许多可变性
And that makes the problem really, really challenging.
这也使得视频分割这个难题 变得特别具有挑战性
So, what are the type of features that are in
Roto Brush有哪些特征
Roto Brush and in the segmentation behind Roto Brush that basically we need to
以及Roto Brush分割视频的特征中 有哪些是我们需要具备的
have? But also features that we need to have in
尤其是其他同类视频分割方法
many, many of this type of video segmentation approaches.
也要具备的特征
So, accuracy we already talked about that.
精确度 我们之前已经提过
Robustness. Robustness also refers to the fact that
健壮性 健壮性除了指算法需要处理
not only the image can be changing. But we actually might have a very, very
变化的图像 而且指算法需要处理多种类型的数据
rich variety of data. And we want this algorithm to work as
我们希望这个算法能很好地处理所有类型的数据
good as possible for all of them. It might work better for ss, better for
这算法可能…可能处理一些数据特别有效率
some of them. Meaning the use of magnet to be less
这意味着有时只需要很少的用户参与度
involved. For some the use of magnet to be more
而在处理一些数据时却需要更多的用户参与度
involved but we want this to be a really good algorithm for all of them.
但是我们希望这算法能适用于所有类型的数据
So it has to be practical and this is related to the user intervation we want
因此算法必须实用 这就涉及到用户的介入 所以我们
to make sure that when the user gets involved things get better because of the
想确保用户的介入只会改善算法整体的运行
involvement of the user and don't get worse so we don't want the user to
而不是使它变得更糟
basically say oh, I'm happy with everything but this and then the user go
举例来说 当用户说 哦 一切都不错除了这有点问题 然后这用户
goes and does something that basically destroys the part that he or she was
做了一些事 我们不希望这些事把他或她满意的部分毁个彻底
already happy with so it has to be a natural work flow and very easy and as we
所以整个算法流程必须是自然流畅 非常简单的
say has to be very computational efficiency so you know we have about 30
而且正如我们所说的 算法需要非常高的计算效率 因为你知道
frames a second in the NTSE American system our, our and similar you know 24
在美国NTSC制式中 一秒大约包含30帧 类似地
to 30 frames between the empty seat and polly systems and we don't want every
我们知道从PAL制式到NTSC制式 影像大致从每秒24帧到每秒30帧
frame to take hours we just want every frame to be done really kind of in an
我们不希望每一帧的处理都要花几个小时 我们希望每一帧都能在
interactive comfortable time. So, the algorithm I'm going to describe
舒适的交互时间内处理完 所以我将要讲到的算法
has four major steps, that we see them here.
有四个主要步骤 已经写在这里了
First of all, we're going to do segmentation one frame to the next frame,
首先 我们要依次在每帧中做分割
then we're going to propagate multiple frames ahead.
然后我们将分割向后传递多帧
And then, we're going to show local correction and I'm going to basically
接着 我将演示第三步——局部矫正 我也将简要地
briefly mention about post-processing which is a concept that we are segmenting
提到第四步——后期处理 这个概念是关于视频分割的
videos, not just still images. And we're going to see many, many very
而不只限于静态图像 我们将列举非常多
cool examples. So, let's start with the localized
很酷的例子 让我们从局部分类来开始
classifiers. So, let me explain what do I mean by
先让我解释下我说的局部分类
localized classifiers. We're going to assume, that we start,
指的是什么 我们假定从分割这一帧
from the segmentation, of a given frame. This segmentation, was obtained either
给定的图像开始 这个工作量是微不足道的
minorly, remember we are talking about segmenting entire videos, so certainly we
记住我们现在要做的是分割整个视频
can ask, once in a while the user, to manually do a segmentation, but we know,
所以我们当然偶尔可以让用户进行手动分割 但我们知道
that we don't actually need that, because we have learned many ways, to do, this
我们不用那么做 因为我们已经学了很多种
type of, stilement segmentation. So we start, from one segmentation.
处理这种静物分割的方法 所以我们从一个分割开始
And we want to propagate this segmentation to the next one.
之后我们会把这个分割传递到下一个
That's going to be our first challenge here.
这将是我们面临的第一个挑战
Now we are going to have what we call local classifiers.
现在我们看到的是局部分类器
So, we're going to put windows centered around the segmentation, around the
我们要把窗口的中心正对分割的部分
boundaries that we have just computed. From each one of these windows that
卡在刚刚计算出来的边界周围 所有的窗口将把图像围起来
basically go all around. So, every one has a window.
所以每个部分都有一个窗口
Every pixel has a window. Or maybe we do every few pixels going
每个像素都有一个窗口 或者我们让一条曲线上每几个重叠的像素有一个窗口
around the curve, with some overlapping, as we have illustrated here.
正如我们在这儿展示的这样
From every one of these, we have very important information.
这儿的每一个窗口 都告诉我们非常重要的信息
So once again, this is just a local window.
再重复一次 这只是局部窗口
Is here because we are in a frame that we're given the segmentation for that
也就是在这儿的窗口 我们现在已经获取了某一帧的分割信息
frame so we're on frame T, we have the boundary and we have the inside and the
令它为第T帧 我们有了边界信息 也就能分出对象内部
outside of the object. Now because we have that we have two very
和对象外部 因此 在窗口中我们拥有了两个
important characteristics in that window. We have a shape prior, that we say okay,
非常重要的特征信息 我们知道了形状先验的信息
we believe that the next frame will have a similar shape, remember frames, are
也就是说 我们认为下一帧图像的形状与上一帧相似
very, very fast, in time so things can not in a normal video change a lot,
记得一帧的时间是非常短的 所以一般说来
between frames. So we have, a shape prior, we also have a
物体在帧与帧之间不会改变太多所以 形状先验成立
color model, so we know what type of colors to expect in the foreground, what
我们还拥有颜色模型 在这个模型中 我们可以预测在前景和背景中
that type colors to expect in the background.
将看到什么颜色
That's for every one of these windows. So let's see how we use that.
这是这些小窗格要做的事 让我们来看看如何使用吧
We are now in frame T, and we want to be able to segment out frame T+1.
我们现在在第T帧 想把第T+1帧分割完成
This we have, as I say, is one of the frames we mark by hand or is one of the
正如我所说 这是我们手动操作的一帧
previous frames, as we're going to see in the next slide when we progress.
或者是根据算法分割好的一帧 我会在下一张幻灯片中讲到
And we have these windows all around, and I want now to segment out the player
这些窗格围绕着物体 现在我想把这位运动员
here. The first thing we do is we basically
分割出来 我们首先要做的是
move these windows to the new frame. Now we can just move them with basically
把这些窗格移动到新的一帧上 我们的移动不用做任何改变
no shifts and that wouldn't be too bad or we can move them following what's called
并且结果不会太坏 或者可以遵循运动估计（Motion Estimation）来移动
motion estimation. Do you remember, when we talked about
回忆一下 以前讲视频压缩的时候
video compression? We talk that we go in a block and look
我们在当前帧选择一个块
for the most similar block in the previous frame.
再到前一帧图像中去寻找最相似的块儿
This what we are doing now. So,
这就是我们正在做的事
for example, we could go into every region and see either backwards or
比如 我们可以锁定每个区域 然后往前或往后找
foreground or forward, we can see what's the closest box, what's the closest local
看看哪个块与它最相近 哪个局部窗格
window. So we can start for example in this local
与它最接近 例如我们可以从这个
window, look around the regions here and then move it the place that we believe is
局部窗格开始 在另一帧中它周围的区域中寻找 然后移动到我们认为与其最接近的窗格
the closest one. We can do the mean squared error, the
我们可以计算均方误 绝对误差 来衡量接近的程度
absolute difference. The same type of approach that we did for
与我们先前讲到视频压缩时
prediction when we were talking about video compression.
判断误差的方法相同
So for every window we have a new position.
我们让每个窗格都有了一个新的位置
Again, if you believe that there is no, too much motion in the image, you can
再重复一次 如果你认为图像几乎没有移动
just copy them to the same position. So we either copy them or we use this
那你可以直接在同一位置上复制 所以要么我们直接复制窗格
motion estimation to move them. So now we have the windows in the new
要么遵循运动估计来移动窗格
frame that we are about to segment. Now remember,
现在我们在要分割的新一帧中也建立了窗格
I'm going to just pick two windows. I'm going to pick a window in the current
还记得第三步吗？ 我将选择两个窗格 一个在当前一帧中
frame and one in the future frame. This is the segmentation that we know.
一个在另一帧中 这儿是我们已经完成的分割
This is where we need to put it. Now we're transferring the red curve, to
这是我们要分割的部分 现在我们正在把红色的曲线转换为蓝色的
the blue, because we have moved, the basic, the block here, but we don't
因为物体(或说这个区域)已经移动了
believe in the blue curve yet. That's the one that we need to adjust.
但是还不能采信蓝色曲线 这里还需要调整
Now, remember that for this, which we call the training.
我们把这张图片叫做“训练图”(training)
Because it's something that we already have,
因为它是已有的东西
we have a shape prior and we also have color distributions.
还有一张形状先验以及颜色分布
So, we have, we say, more or less, this is what we believe should be the curve
我们可以认为它大概就是这里的曲线
here. And these are the distributions of colors
还有颜色分布
in the foreground. I'm in the background.
前景的 后景的
Now why do I write here GMM? This stands for Gaussian mixture models.
我为什么在这儿写上“GMM”呢？ 因为它代表高斯混合模型 (Gaussian mixture models)
That's one way to approximate the distribution of foreground and
是一种模拟前景与后景分布的方法
background. Just think once again about the histogram
再想一下直方图分布
distributions. Now instead of having the histograms we
这次不是用直方图来模拟
want to approximate, approximate them by a parametric function.
而是用参数函数
And that's why we are using for Roto Brush Gaussian mixture models.
这就是我们采用Roto Brush高斯混合模型的原因
But it's not critical now. Just remember, you have a distribution of
但这不是关键 只要记得 你得到了前景颜色的分布
colors for the back, foreground, a distribution of colors for the
和后景颜色的分布
background. For simplicity, just think about
简单来说 想想直方图就行了
histograms. Now that's what we're going to try to
我们要结合这些
combine. To basically find the exact position of
来确定蓝色曲线的准确位置
the blue curve. So once again the red move to the blue
重新说一次 红色曲线要变换成蓝色的
but we want to be able to shift that around.
而蓝色的可以出现在红色的附近(而不完全一样)
So, this is going to provide us some information of where should it be.
这些告诉我们蓝色曲线大概应该在哪里
I'm not going to allow it to change completely, because I'm not expecting a
我不会让蓝色曲线完全改变 因为不期望逐帧得到的形状
complete shape the formation from frame to frame. I'm also not expecting complete
完全改变 我同样不期待
changes in the color, in the pixel values in the image.
颜色 像素值会完全改变
So this provides me a very good prior, about the colors for every pixel, inside
这些是很好的颜色分布的先验 对这里的每个像素
here, I can say, are you more probably foreground or background?
可以指出更可能是前景还是后景
So we can get a picture like this, and the idea is to merge.
由此可以得到这样一副图像 而我们希望把二者结合起来
A shape prior and a color prior. how to merge them is going to be what we
融合这个形状分布先验和颜色分布先验 至于如何将它们融合
are going to explain next. The important part here is that from what
则是后面将要解释的 关键在于从已知的东西
we already know, we can get for every block, kind of a distribution of
我们能得到所有区块
probability of shape and probability of colors, merge them, and then we get the
形状和颜色上的概率分布 融合二者
probability of every pixel being either foreground or background.
就得到了每个像素为前景或后景的概率
That happens for every single one of these blocks that have moved from the
这发生在由前一帧得来的每一个区块
previous frame. And therefore, we put it back, we get
现在我们把它放回去
that for the entire image. And from that for example using graph
就得到了整个图像的概率分布 利用诸如Graph-Cuts算法
cards we can get a segmentation. And from this frame we will be able to go
就可以得到这一帧的分割 由此又可以得到下一帧的
to the next frame. Before that, I have to explain to you how
那之前 需要解释下如何融合
we do this merging. For the merging, we have to remember that
讲到融合 要记住
we have both colors and shape as indicated here.
我们已知的是颜色和形状的先验分布
So for every block, color, and shape, how we combine them.
对于每一个区块 如何融合颜色和形状呢？
The basic idea is what's written here. If you have colors that are well
基本想法写在这里 如果颜色分离得很好了
separated, trust them. If not, trust the shape.
就采信颜色 否则就采信形状
If you're ambivalent, trust both and merge them.
如果二者矛盾 那就一并采信并融合它们
So, we have the color distributions here. From the previous frame.
这里是前一帧得来的颜色分布
We have information from the previous frame, a segmentation that we trust.
从前一帧得到一些信息 一个可信的分割
And we got the shape prior, the color priors.
由此得到了形状分布先验 颜色分布先验
If the color distributions are well separated, so you look at the histograms
如果前景和后景在颜色分布上很好地分离了 就会看到诸如每种颜色的直方图
for example, of every color or a distribution of all of them together, and
或者所有颜色的一个分布
you see that their very well separated, and are multiple ways to measure that.
能看到它们很好地分开来 可以有许多方法来测量这种分离程度
If there was separated. Trust the colors, trust the probability,
如果分割开了 那就相信颜色 相信概率
and use this shape prior very limited. So, the shape prior was somewhere here,
只有限地运用形状先验 假设原来的形状在这里
that was the curve, you say. I'm going to let you be, any place, at a
譬如说是这条曲线 由形状先验图可知
relatively large distance, from what your shed prior predicted, so you basically
新的分割曲线所在的范围可以很大
can go on every pixel that has, certain distance, from the, prior, it's an allow
可以得到这个相对很大的区域中每一个像素
reach, and for the prior. So you get, these two type of
总的来说你有两种概率
probabilities, you merge them, you get your, confidence map, all the
把它们融合 就得到了可信的映射 所有的概率
probability, that we saw in the previous slide.
也就是上一页中我们看到的那个概率分布
That, if you have this, confidence. If you don't trust him to much basically
以上是对颜色分布有信心的情况 假如分布出现更多的重叠
you have that the distributions are more overlapping, then what you do is disband
而无法非常采信 那要做的就是
that had a prior shape, you make it a bit narrow.
把表示形状先验的这个窄带变得窄一些
You say basically I don't want a late the boundary in this particular block to go
我不希望这一区块里的边界
very far from what I predicted, has to be more or less where I predicted.
偏离我的预测太多 多少要在预测附近
And the less you trust the color, because of overlapping, the more narrow you make
重叠造成对颜色的不信任越严重 条带设置得就越窄
those binds. So these are three examples from the
这是视频中的三个例子
video. And these are real examples.
是真实的例子
So this is the back of the player, where the colors were very well separated.
这里是运动员的背部 颜色很好地分离开了
This is the, another region. There is not such a clear separation.
这是另一个区域 分离得不是太好
And look here, even the image tells us the separation
再看这里 连图像上都
between foreground and background is not very good.
分辨不太出前景与后景
For all the cases we get, as we saw in the previous slide, both color and shape.
这些不同情况
The difference is, once we're given the shape prior,
其区别在于 给定形状先验
something like this will be here. Here will be something like this.
这里像这样 这儿像这样
And here will be this. How much we let that shape prior to
而这里像这样 该让形状先验
impose the actual position of the new curve.
给新曲线的位置施加多大的影响呢？
If we trust a lot the color, we basically expand that shape prior a lot.
若对颜色采信地多 就扩展形状先验决定的边界
And we say, be anywhere you want, because I know colors are going to help me.
就是说 随你想在哪里 颜色会帮助你的
We trust that it be less, we see that this is a bit narrow.
对颜色采信地越少 形状边界就越窄
When the color distributions basically don't provide any information, the shape
颜色分布给不出什么信息时
prior comes to the rescue and say, I'm sorry, you cannot change too much.
就靠缩小形状边界来救场 就是说 它不能变动地太多
So it's a very, very narrow band. This always comes from the product.
所以这会是非常窄的条带 这些颜色边界取决于概率
It comes always from the colors of the previous frame.
取决于前一帧的颜色分布
The actual shape of the confidence of the prior depends on the confidence we have
形状先验的实际采信度 取决于颜色先验的采信度
here. These two, we add them, we normalize, and
把二者相加 并正规化
we wait, we get what we solve in the previous example.
就得到了之前例子里的解答
Here for example there is no way to use colors.
例如 在这里没法采信颜色
They are too similar but the shape prior, because the previous frame was so nicely
它们太相近了 不过由于前一帧被良好地分割了
segmented, help us to continue with the segmentation for the next frame and so
形状先验就能帮助我们接着做这一帧的分割
on. This is a very important concept where we
在结合多种信息
merge different types of information to obtain the segmentation that we want.
以得到想要的分割时 这是个很重要的理念
That just illustrate how important this is.
接下来演示下这有多重要
We have here one frame. Segmented.
这是分割了的一帧
We have the horse segmented off and we're going to, want to segment the next frame.
这匹马被分割出来了 接下来要分割下一帧
So first of all why this local. Remember, having this frame, we are
首先 为何是局部的？ 记住 这一帧里
having blogs around it and we do everything local.
围绕马有一些区块 我们都是在局部操作
Because the other lab, they share information, but everything is local.
区块之间会共享信息 但所有操作都是局部的
If we were not to do it, so if we were to consider one entire
如果没有那样做 如果把整帧当作一个区块
frame as one blog. There is so much variability in the
颜色就会太多变
colors, that the distribution basically makes nonsense.
分布就没有什么意义了
And we won't be able to segment the horse.
也就无法把马分割出来
If we use the local, this is what we are going to get all ready.
如果在局部基于颜色分割 结果是这样的
Much, much better using local color models, because we only care about what
得到的东西就会好太多 因为我们只关心
is around each one of the pixels in the boundary.
边界上每个像素点附近的情况
Now there is still problems, with basically, as we see here.
还有一些问题 我们看到这里
The horse is white, the carriage is also white.
马是白的 马车也是白的
So certainly, the color there won't help a lot.
显然颜色就起不到太大作用了
And we see that problem coming here, okay?
问题来了 对吗？
But, that's where the shape prior. This provides both colors and shape for
这时要靠形状先验了 做下一帧时颜色和形状都会用到
the next frame. And that's where it comes to the rescue.
而这里就是形状起作用了
And here, we see what we get when we combine both locality and shape and color
这里显示了把局部性、形状和颜色结合后 得到的东西
priors. We get very nice prior that as I said
这是很好的边界先验分布
before, with an algorithm like graft guides, immediately gets the nice
运用类似于Graph-Cuts的算法 马上就能得到很好的分割
segmentation, and we propagate the segmentation to the next frame.
由此还能得到下一帧的分割
So both local and combining shape and color is very important to get this
因此 要获得准确的分割 局部性 形状和颜色 都很重要
accurate segmentations. We're going to see very soon that the
我们很快将看到
locality's important beyond what I just explained.
局部分割的重要性不仅于此
It's also important to help the user have a much more friendly interaction with the
它也有助于在图像处理上建立更友好的用户交互
images. So, this is how we actually go from one
以上就是如何从上一帧的分割得到这一帧的
frame right to the next frame, but we don't want to do just one frame.
不过我们不止想做一帧
We want to do multiple frames. How do we do that?
而是想做多帧 要怎么做呢？
So the basic first idea that will come to our mind is, okay segment the first
基本思想是 第一帧的分割
frame, go to the next frame. Then, from the segmentation of this
到其下一帧 再从这帧
frame, go to the next one. From the segmentation of this one, go to
到下一帧 这一帧的分割 到下一帧
the next one. And keep going as long as you can, as far
如此就可一直做下去
as you can. But this has one fundamental problem.
然而这种做法有个根本问题
The fundamental problem is the following. This is a frame that we trusted.
问题出现在误差积累上 我们采信这一帧
We trusted it a lot. Maybe because we need the hand
我们很信任它 也许因为是手动分割的
sanitation, maybe because we work very hard on that.
也许因为花费的工作够多
Now, this is the result of the algorithm I just described, based on this.
而这一帧是靠我讲过的算法 从这一帧得出的
This might not be perfect. If I propagate these to the next one,
它也许不太完美 如果我把这传递给下一帧
then the errors I created here, propagate to the next one, which means that my
那么在这儿产生的误差 传递给了下一个 这意味着我的
shape priors error propagate, my color distributions.
形状先验误差传递了  我的颜色分布
Also the estimations for this frame propagate if there are any errors.
以及对这一帧的估计 (如果有错误)  也传递了
One way to address that is to say, okay in order to stabilize the system why
解决办法之一就是  为了稳定系统
don't we let the color priors also to influence here.
为什么我们不让色彩先验亦在此产生影响呢
Why don't we let them keep moving? And also here and also here.
为什么我们不让他们保持前进? 这也是 这也是
This is the friend that we trusted a lot. So let's just have it move forward.
这是我们很相信的朋友 所以让它继续向前
Remember that we are working in blocks. So locally, we let it move forward.
记住我们正在以块工作 所以在局部上 我们让它向前移
And in that way, everybody will get also some of the information that we have from
用这种方法 每一帧都会得到原始帧的一些信息
the original frame. And from the original segmentation that
也从我们非常信任的原始分割中 得到信息
we so much trusted. And in this way, what we get is that our
用这种方法 结果是
segmentation has propagated not only one frame, but has propagated.
我们做的分割不仅传递了一帧
Multiple frames. So, once again the information that we
而且传播到后面的许多帧  所以又一次地
trust, and because we're working locally, it doesn't have to be that we trust it
因为我们的操作是局部性的 所以我们信任的信息不必影响全局
globally. It only has to be that we trust it
只要对局部的影响是可信的就可以了
locally. That information we can propagate
这种可以传递到多个帧的信息
multiple frames to help stabilize the system.
有助于稳定系统
We could actually iterate and use the current segmentation as the initial
我们可以重复这样做 将当前分割作为初始状态
condition or the priors for the next segmentation and so on.
或者作为后面分割的先验等等
That's an option in this type of frameworks.
这种帧可以选择这样操作
But the critical part is to use information that we trust.
但是关键部分是使用我们信任的信息
As many frames ahead as possible. Before I give you some cool examples,
尽可能多的利用上先前的帧 在我举例之前
there's a couple of additional things that we need to do.
我们有几件事要做
One of them is, how are we going to let the user to repair mistakes?
一件是 我们如何让用户修复错误？
No matter how great the algorithm that we develop,
不管我们写的算法多么完美
video segmentation is a very, very tough problem.
视频分割是一个非常非常难的问题
In particular, if we are going to segment two hour movies.
尤其当我们想分割一个两个小时的电影时
So, we need to let the user do repairs in the algorithm.
所以 我们要让用户帮助改善算法的效果
Remember, when we trust a friend, we're really trusted, so we better make sure
记住 当我们相信一个朋友 我们是真的相信  所以我们最好确定
that all the friends, all the way, are in very good shape.
所有的朋友一直处于良好的状态中
So here is an example. We have this progression, and then we
这有个例子 这里有一系列连续帧  然后我们发现
realize that it was good, it was good, but here there is a mistake.
这很好 这很好 但是这里有一个错误
So how are we going to let the user repair that mistake?
所以我们如何让用户修复这个错误？
Here is where once again the work on local blocks helps a lot.
又一次 在局部块上的操作起了很大作用
So we basically want to do that. We want to go and repair it.
所以我们想要这样操作 我们想去修复它
And there is many packages that will help us to repair.
有很多帮助我们修复的包
Basically, I want to illustrate that again.
我想再展示一下刚才的操作
Here we have it. And now we repair it.
这里有错误 现在修复好了
So we repair it inside many different packages, Photoshop, After Effects, you
我们可以用很多不同的包修复它  PS  AE
can just go and move that curve. But of course, remember they were
你只需点一下就可以改变曲线  当然 要记住
propagation before, there was propagation before.
它们是传递过的  这些分割都是传递来的
So that mistake that we had before propagated, propagated, propagated.
这个早已存在的误差 传递 传递 传递
I want to now the correction I did, I want it to propagate as well.
现在 我希望刚才所做的这个修正  也像这样传递下去
I don't want to to propagate backwards, if I'm happy with what happen in the
既然之前的分割都是正确的 我不想它向后传播
past. I don't want my correction here to
我不想这里的校正
influence what happened here because I'm happy with that.
影响这里 因为我对这里已经很满意了
So, here we have everything based on local blocks, local patches.
至此 我们学会了局部块 局部修复的所有内容
And that's great. We go and look at every block, or every
这很好 我们看看每一个块 或者每一个修补
patch, that is effected by my recent repair.
都被最近的修复所影响
And because we have this motion estimation that we did, we know where are
因为我们已经做过运动估计 我们知道
these blocks going in the next frames. We have their position in the future as
这些块在后续帧中的去向 也知道将来它们的位置
well and then we go and do repairs only in those blocks may be we can expand a
接下来我们只在块中做修复 或许我们可以扩展
couple to the side to just make it more continuous repair but we certainly are
到几个边 让修复更加连续 但是确定的是我们一定
not got going to let the propagation of that correction go all the way far away
不会让那个修正传递得太远
here. And that's how we get this local control.
这就是我们局部控制的方法
So these blocks are helping us to get lock and features, and are also helping
所以这些块帮助我们得到局部特征
us to do the interaction must faster. So look what's going to happen now with
也助于我们更快地交互 所以看下修复后会发生什么
this repairs. We just do them and here it is.
我们操作了 这是结果
We have repaired them. Let me show that again to you.
我们把它们修复了 让我再演示一遍
We had a mistake, but we just repaired that mistake.
我们遇到一个错误 但是我们修复了这个错误
We let that repair propagate to the corresponding blocks in future frames.
我们让这个修正传递到后续帧中的相关块
And then we get everything repaired. And then we can continue with this frame,
这样我们把所有的都修复了 接下来继续 从这一帧开始
segmenting forward frames. So, this is very cool, this is the third
分割前面帧 所以 这非常酷 这是第三步
step that basically is the local correction.
局部修复
The final thing is, we have, so far done segmentation frame by frame.
最后的事情是 目前为止 我们已经逐帧进行了分割
This is a movie. We need the segmentation to be coherent,
这是一部电影  我们希望这些分割是逐帧连续且一致的
consistent across frames. One way of doing that is basic to smooth
达到这种效果的方法之一是使之平滑化
this out. We have these segments per frame.
我们每帧都有分割
We're going to smooth them out across time, regularize them to make them look
我们要让这些分割的过渡是平滑的 规范化它们以使来让它们看上去更好些
better and then when I basically show you what happens.
接下来让你看看发生了什么
So you see here you might be able. To see that the boundaries are a bit
所以你看这里 这的边缘有点粗糙
rough here, and are much nicer here. We basically take the segmentation of
这儿就好多了 我们将多个帧的分割一起平滑一下
multiple frames and we smooth them out together, to get from this rough.
使之从粗糙到平滑
Segmentation to much nicer, much smooth segmentation, that help us either to put
这样就可以把这个物体放到其他电影里
this object in other movies, or to do different effects.
或者做出其他效果
So now, it's time to show, examples of this very cool technique.
所以现在 是时候来展示下 这个很酷技术的例子
This is an example that we have seen a number of times before.
这是一个我们看过很多遍的例子
So, here we have multiple examples. But I'm going to run them now.
所以 在这我们有好几个例子 但是我现在不准备演示
We have segmented out here, the person. He looks very nice.
我们已经对这个人做了分割  效果看上去非常好
He has all the components. He has the repair, the smoothing,
他经过了各种处理  修复 光滑
everything, and looks really, really nice.
所有的 看上去真的真的很好
Here is an example that we have seen multiple times and we see it with the
这是个我们看过多次的例子 我们在背景模糊后
particular case where we blur the background.
在背景模糊的实例中我们见过这个
This is a special effect that we have seen in the past, in one of the
这是我们以前看过的一个特效
introductory videos before. We segmented out the players and then we
在之前的一个介绍视频中出现过 我们把运动员分割
put them in a blurry background to enhance the players and call the
并把他们放到一个模糊的背景中 来增强运动员
attention of the viewer to the players. Some addition and really nice examples
将观看者的注意力吸引至运动员上 这还有其他的好例子
of, of special effects. Here we have the original one.
特效的例子 这是原始视频
And there is a special filter. You can see the lady surfing that has
这是经过滤波的 你可以看到冲浪的女士已经被筛选出了
been filtered out. So we first have to segment this with all
所以首先我们要分割出这个
the problems of splashes from the water, topological changes occurring as we see
难点在于飞溅的水滴 以及这里的拓扑改变
here. Once we segment that out, we can make
一旦我们把它分割出来
very nice special effects, like here. Here we changed the light.
我们可以对它做非常漂亮的特效  像这儿一样 我们改变了人身上的光照
In the person, as you can see. We don't have to affect the back ground,
正如你看的那样 我们不必影响背景
because we have segmented the foreground out.
因为我们已经把前景分割了出来
And here is the compulsive that we have seen before.
这是我们见过的合成
Everything starts from segmenting this very tough image.
一切从这个糟糕的原图开始
I want to keep giving you examples. I think this is quite cool.
我想再给你们举些例子 我觉得这真的很酷
This is another example where we basically segment out the player from the
这又有个例子 我们把运动员从背景中分割出来
background. Look how difficult this problem is.
看这个问题多么困难
The background is all blue and white. Or blue and gray like the player.
背景全是蓝色或白色的 或者说蓝色和灰色 跟运动员一样
A lot of confusion, but we have shape, and that helps a lot.
一切都混淆在一起 但是我们有形状 这帮了我们不少
And once we segment this player out, we can basically modify the background, for
一旦把运动员分离出来 我们就可以修改背景
example, significantly blurried. And this is also based on the just, the
比如 将之模糊化  这也基于
concept that I just explained to you of segmenting the foreground out.
刚才向你们解释过的 把前景抠出来的概念
For this particular, there are some additions on not only mottling the
对于本例 不仅要对前景色建模
foreground colors. We can also model the background colors.
我们也可以将背景色建模
All what I explain now, is let's model the program, color and shape.
我之前一直再讲 让我们给前景的颜色和形状建模
Why not to do all this some learning of the background?
为什么不对背景研究下呢？
You can do that and then you get improvement in your results.
这样对结果会有改善
But again, the concepts are very similar. And, I want to give you one more example.
但是 概念非常相似 我再举个例子
So, here is an outer special effect, where we basically, take the actor here,
所以 这是一个特殊效果 我们将演员分割出来
segment it out, and we can repeat it in multiple positions.
在多个位置上重复
Again, the big challenge here is to segment it out.
同样 这里的最大挑战是把他分割出来
Here, there is very good basic contrast between the actor, in particular with the
这里的对比非常强烈
shirt and the background, so color would be very important here.
尤其在衬衫和背景之间 所以颜色对于分割是非常重要的
But also the shape the actor is moving, but it's not completely deforming, so the
但是同样演员的形状在移动 但是不是完全地变形
shape prior is critical. So this gives us an idea of what's behind
所以形状先验很有用  所以这告诉我们
one of the popular video segmentation techniques in particularly Roto Brush
这个最受欢迎的视频分割技术的原理 尤其是旋转笔刷
which is incorporated inside Abobe's After Effect.
旋转笔刷功能被合并进了 Adobe 的 AE 中
And we have seen it has many components. It uses shape.
我们看到这个技术的实现有很多方法 它利用形状
It uses color. It uses localized structures, localized
利用颜色 利用局部结构 局部学习
learning. Both to be able to do more accurate
这些都能有助于更精准地预测
predictions. And also to make it more friendly to the
当用户需要做修正时
user when the user needs to make corrections.
这些方法也方便了用户操作
All those concepts put together is what leads to this very, very high accuracy
这些概念加在一起就形成了这种精度高
and very user-friendly video segmentation.
而且对用户友好的视频分割
Thank you very much. I hope you enjoyed this and I will see
非常感谢 希望你享受学习
you in the next video. Thank you.
下节视频见 谢谢【未完成版本】